[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
The simplest form of ascent a gradient says when an estimated
يوضح أبسط أشكال التدرج العشوائي متى يحدث
gradient one data point at a time.
التدرج التقديري في كل نقطة على حدة.
So lets see what that looks like.
لنرى كيف يبدو ذلك.
We're back to our gradient, the sun setting where we are going to start,
لقد عدنا إلى التدرج، وضع الشمس حيث سنبدأ،
from some point in space.
من نقطة ما في الفضاء.
We're going to compute the gradient of the likelihood function,
وسنقوم بحساب التدرج لدالة الاحتمالية،
take a little step in that space, then compute the gradient again,
نتحرك قليلًا في تلك المساحة، ثم نحسب التدرج مرة أخرى،
take another little step, another little step, and another little step.
ثم نتحرك قليلًا خطوة بخطوة.
And this is the algorithm on the right that we'll be using
وهذه هي الخوارزمية على اليمين التي سنستخدمها
throughout this module and before that.
على مدار هذه الوحدة وما قبلها.
The question here is how expensive is this algorithm?
السؤال ما هي تكلفة هذه الخوارزمية؟
Let's look at the case of logistic regression,
دعونا ننظر في حالة الانحدار اللوجستي،
just to remind ourselves of how expensive that is.
فقط لتذكير أنفسنا بتكلفة ذلك.
What we need to do here is sum function over each data point.
ما نحتاج إليه هنا هو دالة معينة تنقسم على كل نقطة بيانات.
And you can think about it as the contribution to the gradient the data
ويمكنك التفكير في الأمر على أنه المساهمة في تدرج نقاط البيانات
point xi, yi has, and we're adding those up through each data point.
التي تمتلكها xi و yi، ونضيفهم لكل نقطة بيانات.
And so, I'm going to denote here by this term,
سأشير هنا إلى هذا المصطلح،
the derivative l subscript i with respect to
مشتق ل li بالنسبة إلى
the priority wj is the contribution of i data point to the gradient.
الأولوية wj وهي مساهمة من نقاط البيانات i بالقوة الأسية المتمثلة في التدرج.
And what we're doing here Is summing up each one of these contributions
ونقوم بجمع كل واحدة من هذه المساهمات
in order to compute the final gradient that we're going to take,
من أجل حساب التدرج النهائي الذي سنأخذه،
the final update for the parameters.
التحديث النهائي للمتغيرات.
So how computationally costly is it to do this approach?
كم هي مكلفة من الناحية الحسابية؟
So let's ask that question.
دعونا نسأل هذا السؤال.
So for example, if I were to say
إذن، على سبيل المثال، إذا كنت سأقول
computing the contribution of one data point takes me one millisecond.
حساب مساهمة نقطة بيانات واحدة يأخذ 1/1000 من الثانية.
It's really fast, it only takes me one millisecond.
إنه سريع حقا، لا يستغرق الأمر أكثر من ملي ثانية.
When I have 1,000 data points, then that's not too bad.
عندما يكون لدي 1000 نقطة بيانات، فهذا ليس سيئًا للغاية.
1,000 milliseconds is one second.
1000 ميلي ثانية هي ثانية واحدة.
I don't feel too bad about that outcome.
لا أشعر بالسوء تجاه هذه النتيجة.
What if you have a much more complex model, like a neural network or
فإذا كان لديك نموذج أكثر تعقيدًا، مثل الشبكة العصبية
something, where one update takes 1 second instead of 1 millisecond, and
حيث يستغرق أحد التحديثات 1 ثانية بدلاً من 1 ميلي ثانية،
you have 1000 data points?
ولديك 1000 نقطة بيانات؟
Now computing 1 step of gradient requires 1000 seconds,
تتطلب الآن الحوسبة 1 من التدرج 1000 ثانية،
which if you can't do this in your head, I can't.
التي إذا لم تستطع فعل هذا في عقلك، أنا لا أستطيع.
By Cheetah is 16.7 minutes.
16.7 دقيقة.
Now things are getting a little bit more complicated.
الآن أصبحت الأمور أكثر تعقيدًا بعض الشيء.
So 16.7 minutes is a lot to wait, but
الانتظار 16.7 دقيقة يعتبر انتظارًا طويلًا
a thousand data points is nothing.
1000 نقاط البيانات تعتبر لا شيء.
We said YouTube has five billion data points per day or more.
لقد قلنا إن YouTube لديه خمسة مليارات نقطة بيانات في اليوم أو أكثر.
So let's say that we're going back to the one millisecond case.
لنفترض أننا سنعود إلى حالة المللي الثانية.
It only takes 1 millisecond to compute that gradient contribution, but
يستغرق الأمر 1 ميلي ثانية فقط لحساب تلك المساهمة في التدرج
you have 10 million data points, what happens?
ولديك 10 ملايين نقطة بيانات، ماذا يحدث؟
Well the total time now becomes 2.8 hours.
يصبح الوقت الإجمالي الآن 2.8 ساعة.
So things are starting to get nasty but again,
لذلك بدأت الأمور تصبح سيئة ولكن مرة أخرى،
10 million data points is not that much.
10 ملايين نقطة بيانات ليست بالقدر الكبير.
YouTube has five billion, ten billion more per day.
يحتوي YouTube على خمسة مليارات، أو عشرة مليارات يوميًا أو أكثر.
So what happens if you have ten billion data points and
ماذا يحدث إذا كان لديك عشرة مليارات نقطة بيانات
it takes you just one millisecond to compute that creating contribution?
واستغرق منك ملي ثانية لحساب تلك المساهمة؟
Then it's going to take us 10 billion milliseconds,
أي 10 مليارات ميلي ثانية،
which I cheated here, it's 115.7 days.
وهو 115.7 يومًا.
So it's going to take about four months, approximately,
لذلك سيستغرق الأمر حوالي أربعة أشهر، تقريبًا،
just to compute one gradient.
فقط لحساب تدرج واحد.
And if you remember from implementation,
وإذا كنت تتذكر من عملية التنفيذ،
you have to do many gradient updates before you converge.
يجب عليك القيام بالعديد من تحديثات التدرج قبل التحويل.
So this is definitely not going to work, you need to do something about it.
ھذا ﺑﺎﻟﺗﺄﮐﯾد ﻟن ﯾﻌﻣل، ﯾﺟب ﻋﻟﯾك اﻟﻘﯾﺎم ﺑﺷﻲء ﻣﺎ ﺣﯾﺎل ذﻟك.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]